SYED UMAIR NAFEES

Address: D-49, Rufi Spring Flowers, Scheme-33, Karachi
Cell: +92-321-3837332 • Email: umair.nafees1987@gmail.com

ACCOUNTING & FINANCE MANAGER

To pursue a challenging position in Finance department of Multinational companies; s Sector based companies offering genuine opportunity for career progression

KEY SKILLS

Full Accounting Life Cycle

• Cost Reduction & Budgeting

- Bookkeeping & Recording
- Internal/External Audits
- Internal Control Deployment
- Statement Reconciliations
- Policies & Procedures
- Change-Focused Initiatives
- Process Improvements
- Cross-Functional Leadership

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Demonstrated achievements and extensive experience in the designing, development, implementation and management of comprehensive core accounting, budgeting, financial reporting, and regulatory compliance systems for high growth organizations.

Successful in linking accounting and finance with general operations to provide financial leadership for strategic planning, business development and commercialization.

Developed customized financial strategies and solutions to meet the needs of clients and ability to diagnose and report issues to return organizations to economic stability.

Skilled in forecasting, budget planning, implementation and reporting deadlines. Perfect review of adequacy and effectiveness of the organization's system of internal control.

Possess great ability of taking initiatives that will enhance company performance, profitability and achievement of corporate goals

WORK EXPERIENCE

DOW UNIVERSITY OF HEALTH SCIENCES

Accounts Officer • Sep 2016 — Present

Rendered keen eye for details to conduct internal audit to assess the adequacy, effectiveness and efficiency of the established controls and procedures as well as ensure procedures, policies and regulations strict compliance.

Key Accomplishments:

- ✓ Built collaborative rapport with the Functional heads for relevant audit matters, generated and reviewed detailed as per the management requirement and ensured relevant taxes deduction and withheld on vendors' payments.
- ✓ Conducted periodic reviews of the fixed asset schedule to determine dispositions and reconciled balance in fixed asset ledger to the general ledger.
- Rendered keen eye for details to perform accounting activities as per established accounting standards.
- ✓ Exercised hands-on approach and effective controls to initiate and control procurement process complied with the regulations of Sindh Public Procurement Regulatory Authority (SPPRA).
- ✓ Reconciled fixed assets subsidiary ledgers/accounts and verified the accuracy of all journal entries.
- Successfully designed and implemented process and policy improvements related to the fixed asset process.

IT ENABLERS (PRIVATE) LIMITED

Senior Accountant • Jul 2018 — Present

Successful validation of accounting inputs to ensure correctness & accuracy to achieve desired results also carried-out Accounting & Financial matters of organization, also conducted cash audits according to audit plan.

Key Accomplishments:

- ✓ Generated financial and operational reports accurately, also drafted audit reports to highlight the findings and problems observed during the audit and propose recommendations to mitigate the problems.
- ✓ Steered efforts towards monitoring the timely implementation of the management actions recommended in the audit report, also conducted special inspections at the request of senior management.

ATHAR ECOMMERCE SOLUTIONS FZE

Senior Accountant • Aug 2015 — Sep 2016

Generated monthly Financial Statements, Schedules and Reports by collecting, analyzing and summarizing account information, also evaluated revenues, expenses and purchases to ensure record update in ERP system.

Key Accomplishments:

- ✓ Maintained and updated General Ledger, handled EOBI matters, reconciled statements for bank accounts, also verified and recorded reconciliation of credit card payments, also complied Financial policies and procedures.
- ✓ Leveraged keen insight to review and verify suppliers statement of accounts with ERP record on weekly basis and resolve the discrepancies made all payments to suppliers as per agreed terms.
- ✓ Generated monthly staff payroll and disbursement in bank accounts, managed petty cash and updated transactions in ERP, updated all fixed asset records, as well as prepared different financial reports as per management request.

MAC WORLD LOGISTIC LLC (DUBAI)

Accounts Executive • June-2013 — May-2015

Updated and recorded all financial information in accounting software; generated trial balance, Journal Vouchers and record into the software, as well as maintained cash and bank book, general ledger, and trial balance.

Key Accomplishments:

- ✓ Conducted detailed bank reconciliation statement and correspondence with banks as well debtor and creditors.
- ✓ Finalized financial Statements, maintained fixed assets register and recorded depreciation accordingly.

PRIOR EXPERIENCE

Internal Audit Assistant | Oct 2011 — Mar 2012 | CIM SHIPPING INC.

Business Development Officer | Mar 2008 — May 2008 | ABN AMRO BANK

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

ACCA • ACCA UK • 2010 — Present

Masters in Economics & Finance • University of Karachi • 2009 — 2011

Bachelors of Commerce • University of Karachi • 2005 — 2007